# **Georgios Antzigai**

Phone +447874087867

E-mail <u>george.adzhygai@gmail.com</u>

Citizenship EU, Greece Residence London, UK

LinkedIn <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ayorgo">https://www.linkedin.com/in/ayorgo</a>

GitHub https://github.com/ayorgo

StackOverflow <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/users/4755520/ayorgo">https://stackoverflow.com/users/4755520/ayorgo</a>

The latest version of this CV <a href="https://github.com/ayorgo/cv/blob/master/Georgios-Antzigai-CV.pdf">https://github.com/ayorgo/cv/blob/master/Georgios-Antzigai-CV.pdf</a>

## **Summary**

Full stack machine learning engineer able to deliver solutions starting from data collection to establishing **Continuous Integration** pipelines and exposing the resulting model via **REST**ful **API**s.

I have solid experience in **inferential statistics** (point estimates, confidence/credible intervals, hypothesis/significance testing, time series analysis), supervised **machine-learning** (logit, k-NN, decision trees, ensemble boosting/bagging) and **exploratory data analysis** (data wrangling, data visualization) with applications in **Python** (statsmodels, scikit-learn, pandas, NumPy, matplotlib, seaborn) and **R** (stats, dplyr, tidyr, ggplot2) using relational databases and various dialects of **SQL** (MS SQL Server, SQLite).

# **Experience**

#### **Lead Data Scientist**

Nov 2018 – Present time

## ETX Capital etxcapital.com

Leading the team of two data scientists

#### **Data Scientist**

May 2018 - Nov 2018

## ETX Capital etxcapital.com

Applying python to machine learning, data analysis, and reporting.

- Established the python development and deployment pipelines for the company
- Built a classification model using scikit-learn + statsmodels packages for the model itself and pandas + matplotlib
   + seaborn for exploratory data analysis and data cleansing
- Productionised the above model in a form of RESTful APIs using Flask and Microsoft IIS
- Delivered numerous reporting solutions of various complexity using python and T-SQL

## **Self studying Data Science**

Apr 2017 – May 2018

I quit my software development job to pursue my passion and dedicate all of my time and resources to studying probability, statistics, data analysis and machine learning

## Software Engineer

Jun 2015 - Mar 2017 (1 year 10 months)

#### Zopa zopa.com

Worked on company's peer-to-peer lending platform:

- As a software engineer designed and enhanced core parts of the platform such as matching engine and repayment processing using C#
- As an occasional data analyst built advanced reporting solutions in T-SQL

# **Experienced Engineer**

Jun 2014 - Feb 2015 (9 months)

### InsightSoftware.com insightsoftware.com

Contributed to both server and client ends of company's bespoke BI system:

- Fixed and enhanced system's core SQL generating engine written in C#
- Maintained local JavaScript-based SVG graphics library including thorough refactoring, performance enhancements and development of key new features

## .NET Developer

Apr 2013 - May 2014 (1 year 2 months)

### EPAM Systems, Barclay's development center epam.com

Maintained, redesigned and enhanced corporate banking software within various teams or acting independently:

- Developed a set of multi-tier WCF services
- Created a data import and processing tool using advanced SQL and existing scheduling engine
- Set up continuous integration pipelines for the above-mentioned projects using TeamCity along with unit testing, code quality control (StyleCop and Sonar), and NuGet package management

## .NET Web Developer

Sep 2011 - Apr 2013 (1 year 7 months)

#### Terrasoft <u>bpmonline.com</u>

Developed a web-based CRM on both front and back ends:

- · Created a number of UI web controls using ExtJS, CSS, and HTML
- Integrated the Highcharts interactive library
- Developed various back-end solutions using C#, WCF, ASP.NET, and T-SQL

## Senior System Dev. Consultant

Feb 2006 - Apr 2011 (5 years)

### SimCorp Ukraine LLC simcorp.com

Developed and maintained custom investment management system within a team of 3 developers:

- Built data extraction/analysis utility using Dyalog APL and PL/SQL
- Took part in various development projects across the company as a senior consultant

### **Education**

# National Technical University of Ukraine "Kyiv Polytechnic Institute"

2005 - 2007

#### Solid-state physics, PhD study (not complete)

Approximate analytical model of anisotropic coordinate-sensitive radiation detector, comparison to numerical 3D-simulation. With the numerical simulation, a system of second-order nonlinear differential equations was solved taking into account the heats released (absorbed) by eddy thermoelectric currents:

- Snarskii A. A. Adzhigai G. V. Ascheulov A. A. Coordinate-sensitive anisotropic radiation detector. Analytical description and numerical simulation. Journal of Thermoelectricity. 2005, No. 1. - p.80-86.
- Snarskii A. A. Adzhigai G. V. Bezsudnov I. V. On the inherent figure of merit of thermoelectric composites. Journal
  of Thermoelectricity. 2005, No.4. p.74-81. <a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/cond-mat/0609447">http://arxiv.org/abs/cond-mat/0609447</a>

## National Technical University of Ukraine "Kyiv Polytechnic Institute"

1999 - 2005

Applied mathematics, MSc

#### Courses

## **Machine Learning by Stanford University**

Jan 2017

Coursera https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/records/AL4F455VW4DX